bennettlane.com 2015-03-30

# Privacy Statement — Bennett Lane Winery - Napa Valley

BennettLaneWinery is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the BennettLaneWinery Web site and governs data collection and usage. By using the BennettLaneWinery website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

 **Collection of your Personal Information**

BennettLaneWinery collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. BennettLaneWinery also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by BennettLaneWinery. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by BennettLaneWinery for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the BennettLaneWinery Web site.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through BennettLaneWinery public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: BennettLaneWinery does not read any of your private online communications.

BennettLaneWinery encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from BennettLaneWinery so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. BennettLaneWinery is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the BennettLaneWinery and BennettLaneWinery family of Web sites.

 **Use of your Personal Information**

BennettLaneWinery collects and uses your personal information to operate the BennettLaneWinery Web site and deliver the services you have requested. BennettLaneWinery also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from BennettLaneWinery and its affiliates. BennettLaneWinery may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

BennettLaneWinery does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. BennettLaneWinery may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, BennettLaneWinery may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to BennettLaneWinery, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

BennettLaneWinery does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

BennettLaneWinery keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within BennettLaneWinery, in order to determine what BennettLaneWinery services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within BennettLaneWinery to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

BennettLaneWinery Web sites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on BennettLaneWinery or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of BennettLaneWinery; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of BennettLaneWinery, or the public.

 **Use of Cookies**

The BennettLaneWinery Web site use "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize BennettLaneWinery pages, or register with BennettLaneWinery site or services, a cookie helps BennettLaneWinery to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same BennettLaneWinery Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the BennettLaneWinery features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the BennettLaneWinery services or Web sites you visit.

 **Security of your Personal Information**

BennettLaneWinery secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. BennettLaneWinery secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

 **Changes to this Statement**

BennettLaneWinery will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. BennettLaneWinery encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how BennettLaneWinery is protecting your information.

 **Contact Information**

BennettLaneWinery welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that BennettLaneWinery has not adhered to this Statement, please contact BennettLaneWinery at [info@bennettlane.com](https://mail.google.com/mail/?view=cm&fs=1&tf=1&to=info@bennettlane.com). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem. 

We may contract with third party marketing companies to serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet. They may collect non-personal information about your visits to our website, and your interaction with our products and services. They may also use non-personal information about your visits to this and other websites to target advertisements for goods and services. These targeted advertisements may appear on other websites that you visit. The anonymous information is collected through the use of technology such as Cookies and Web Beacons, which are industry standard. No Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”) is collected in this process. 

You may opt-out of the use of your information for tailored advertising purposes. To learn more about the use of this information or to choose not to have this information used by our third-party advertising partner by opting out, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative by clicking [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). If you delete your Cookies, use a different browser, or buy a new computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choice.
